class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> waste_management_in_agriculture = [

QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary objective of waste management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Profit maximization",
"B. Environmental conservation",
"C. Rapid disposal",
"D. Land expansion"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The primary objective of waste management in agriculture is environmental conservation. Proper waste management helps in preserving the environment and maintaining ecological balance.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following is a common agricultural waste product that can be recycled for energy generation?",
options: [
"A. Pesticides",
"B. Plastic bags",
"C. Crop residues",
"D. Fertilizers"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Crop residues are a common agricultural waste product that can be recycled for energy generation. They can be used to produce bioenergy through processes like biomass combustion or biofuel production.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the significance of composting in agricultural waste management?",
options: [
"A. It accelerates waste decomposition",
"B. It increases waste volume",
"C. It reduces soil fertility",
"D. It promotes water pollution"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'Composting is significant in agricultural waste management because it accelerates waste decomposition. It transforms organic waste into nutrient-rich compost, enhancing soil fertility and structure.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "4. Which government agency or organization is typically involved in regulating and monitoring waste management practices in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)",
"B. Federal Aviation Administration (FAA)",
"C. Department of Education",
"D. National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is typically involved in regulating and monitoring waste management practices in agriculture to ensure compliance with environmental standards.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the primary purpose of using cover crops in sustainable agricultural practices?",
options: [
"A. Weed control",
"B. Soil erosion prevention",
"C. Pest extermination",
"D. Increasing crop yield"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The primary purpose of using cover crops in sustainable agricultural practices is soil erosion prevention. Cover crops help protect the soil from erosion, improve soil structure, and enhance water retention.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "6. How can precision farming technologies contribute to better waste management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. By increasing water usage",
"B. By optimizing resource use",
"C. By promoting overuse of fertilizers",
"D. By reducing crop diversity"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'Precision farming technologies contribute to better waste management in agriculture by optimizing resource use. They enable farmers to apply inputs more precisely, reducing waste and environmental impact.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the term for the process of converting organic waste into biogas through anaerobic digestion?",
options: [
"A. Incineration",
"B. Composting",
"C. Biomass combustion",
"D. Methanization"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'The process of converting organic waste into biogas through anaerobic digestion is called methanization. This process is an environmentally friendly way to manage organic waste.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "8. In integrated pest management (IPM), what is the emphasis on controlling pests?",
options: [
"A. Extermination through chemicals",
"B. Biological control methods",
"C. Indiscriminate use of pesticides",
"D. Complete reliance on genetically modified crops"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'Integrated pest management (IPM) emphasizes biological control methods for pest management. It promotes a holistic approach, incorporating natural predators and reducing reliance on chemical pesticides.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "9. What role does the recycling of agricultural plastic play in waste management?",
options: [
"A. Increased landfill use",
"B. Soil pollution",
"C. Resource conservation",
"D. Greenhouse gas emissions"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'The recycling of agricultural plastic plays a crucial role in waste management by contributing to resource conservation. Recycling reduces the demand for new materials and minimizes environmental impact.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "10. What is the primary benefit of using no-till farming practices in relation to waste management?",
options: [
"A. Increased soil erosion",
"B. Reduced carbon sequestration",
"C. Enhanced water runoff",
"D. Improved soil structure"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'The primary benefit of using no-till farming practices in relation to waste management is improved soil structure. No-till farming helps prevent soil erosion and promotes water retention.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "11. Which of the following is an example of non-point source pollution in agricultural waste management?",
options: [
"A. Controlled release of pesticides",
"B. Treated wastewater discharge",
"C. Runoff from fields with excess nutrients",
"D. Proper disposal of crop residues"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Runoff from fields with excess nutrients is an example of non-point source pollution in agricultural waste management. It occurs when rain or irrigation water carries nutrients into water bodies.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "12. What is the primary purpose of using green manure in agricultural waste management?",
options: [
"A. Weed control",
"B. Enhancing soil fertility",
"C. Increasing water usage",
"D. Accelerating waste decomposition"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The primary purpose of using green manure in agricultural waste management is enhancing soil fertility. Green manure crops are grown and then plowed into the soil to improve its nutrient content.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "13. How does agroforestry contribute to sustainable waste management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. By promoting monoculture",
"B. By increasing water runoff",
"C. By diversifying crops and reducing waste",
"D. By depleting soil nutrients"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Agroforestry contributes to sustainable waste management in agriculture by diversifying crops and reducing waste. The integration of trees with crops helps enhance ecosystem services and reduce environmental impact.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "14. Which of the following is a benefit of using biopesticides in agricultural pest management?",
options: [
"A. Indiscriminate killing of beneficial insects",
"B. Residual soil contamination",
"C. Minimal harm to non-target organisms",
"D. Resistance development in pests"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'A benefit of using biopesticides in agricultural pest management is minimal harm to non-target organisms. Biopesticides are typically more selective, causing less harm to beneficial insects and the environment.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "15. How can crop rotation be an effective strategy in agricultural waste management?",
options: [
"A. By depleting soil nutrients",
"B. By promoting soil erosion",
"C. By reducing reliance on synthetic fertilizers",
"D. By encouraging monoculture"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Crop rotation can be an effective strategy in agricultural waste management by reducing reliance on synthetic fertilizers. It helps maintain soil fertility and prevents nutrient depletion.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "16. What is the primary purpose of using biological pest control methods in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Indiscriminate pesticide use",
"B. Targeted pest eradication",
"C. Soil degradation",
"D. Increased chemical residues in crops"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The primary purpose of using biological pest control methods in agriculture is targeted pest eradication. These methods involve the use of natural predators or pathogens to control pest populations.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "17. How does the practice of water harvesting contribute to sustainable agricultural waste management?",
options: [
"A. By increasing water runoff",
"B. By promoting water scarcity",
"C. By reducing soil erosion",
"D. By encouraging over-irrigation"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Water harvesting contributes to sustainable agricultural waste management by reducing soil erosion. It helps capture and store rainwater, preventing runoff and promoting efficient water use.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "18. What is the role of the farmer in the context of waste management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Indiscriminate disposal of waste",
"B. Compliance with environmental regulations",
"C. Excessive use of chemical fertilizers",
"D. Ignoring sustainable practices"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The role of the farmer in waste management in agriculture involves compliance with environmental regulations. Farmers play a crucial role in adopting sustainable practices and proper waste disposal methods.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "19. How does agroecology contribute to sustainable waste management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. By promoting monoculture",
"B. By depleting soil nutrients",
"C. By emphasizing biodiversity and ecological balance",
"D. By encouraging excessive pesticide use"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Agroecology contributes to sustainable waste management in agriculture by emphasizing biodiversity and ecological balance. It promotes practices that enhance natural processes and reduce environmental impact.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "20. What is the environmental impact of improper disposal of agricultural chemicals?",
options: [
"A. Minimal impact on ecosystems",
"B. Soil and water pollution",
"C. Enhanced soil fertility",
"D. Promotion of biodiversity"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'The environmental impact of improper disposal of agricultural chemicals includes soil and water pollution. Inappropriate disposal can lead to contamination, affecting ecosystems and human health.'
)

  ];